Guide to the Colt Press Records, 1920-1973
Department of Special Collections
Colt Press Records,
1920-1973
Special Collections M0240
Colt Press.
3.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased from Brickrow Bookshop, San Francisco, 1973.
Scope and Content
The Colt Press Papers is a collection of business records and correspondence of the Colt Press of San Francisco, California. The business records include: 1) duplicate copies of invoices, 2) checks and bank statements, 3) ledgers, 4) income and sales tax returns, 5) legal contracts and agreements and other financially related material. The correspondence includes letters to and from various people some of whom are: 1) Henry Miller, 2) Valenti Angelo, 3) Frederic Goudy, 4) William Saroyan, 5) Edmund Wilson, 6) Elmer Adler, 7) Beatrice Ward, 8) Robinson Jeffers, 9) John Steinbeck and 10) Paul Bennett.
Container List
- ADLER, ELMER (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1941, Feb. 25.Princeton, New Jersey. Adler to [Jane] Grabhorn., ALS 2pp.
- ANGELO, VALENTI (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. 1969, June 11.Bronxville, N.Y. Vale[nti] [Angelo] to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS. 1p.
  - 2. Three drawings by Angelo - suggested colophons for the Jumbo Press.
- BENNETT, PAUL A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. 1937, July 7.Brooklyn, N.Y. Bennett to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1937, Nov. 10.Brooklyn, N.Y. Paul [A. Bennett] to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 2pp.
  - 3. 1937, Nov. 22.Brooklyn, N.Y. Paul [A. Bennett] to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 2pp.
  - 4. 1938, Feb. 15.Brooklyn, N.Y. Paul [A. Bennett] to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1938, March 22.Brooklyn, N.Y. Paul [A. Bennet] to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 2pp.
- BENTLEY, WILDER (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. 1937, Nov. 19.Berkeley, Ca. W. B[entley] to [Jane Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 2pp.
  - 2. 1938, Feb. 16.Berkeley, Ca. W.B. to J.G. re: typography., AL 2pp.
  - 3. 1939, July 21.Berkeley, Ca. Wilder [Bentley] to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 2pp.
- CARY, MELBERT B., JR. (The Press of Woolly Whale) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. 1937, July 9.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1937, Sept. 9.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn re: publishing matters., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1937, Oct. 7.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1937, Oct. 22.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1938, July 7.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 6. 1939, Oct. 25.New York. Cary to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 7. 1940, April 22.New York. Cary to Robert Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
- CERF, BENNETT A. (Random House, Inc.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1. 1939, Oct. 2.New York. Bennett to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
- EMMONS, EARL H. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1. 1938, May 9.New York. Emmons to Jumbo re: tribute to Frederic Goudy., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1938, May 10.New York. Emmons to Jumbo re: tribute to Frederic Goudy., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1938, May 26.New York. Emmons to Jumbo re: tribute to Frederic Goudy., TLS 1p.
- EVERSON, WILLIAM (BROTHER ANTONINUS) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1. 1949, [Mar. 25].Berkeley, Ca. Bill [Everson] to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 2. 1952, Jan. 10.Oakland, Ca. Brother Antonius to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 3. 1952, Jan. 27.Oakland, Ca. Brother Antonius to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 4. ND.Berkeley, Ca. Bill [Everson] to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
- GARNETT, PORTER (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1. [1937],Sunday. Pittsburgh, Pensylvania. Garnett to Martha Jane [Grabhorn] re: Grabhorn Press., ALS 2pp.
  - 2. 1937, June 38.Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Garnett to Spoofer re: printing., ALS 2pp.
  - 3. 1947,Tuesday. NP. Garnett to Bob [Grabhorn] re: typography., TL 1p.
  - 4. 1948, Sept. 4.NP. Porter to Clink re: writing., TLS 2pp.
  - 5. 1950, Mar. 17.NP. Porter Garnett to Carl Rollins re: typography., TL 3pp.
  - 6. 1950, April 12.Calistoga, Ca. Porter a Edna to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS and ALS 2pp.
  - 7. 1950, April 12.Calistoga, Ca. Porter to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 8. 1950, May 25.NP. Porter and Edna to Jane [Grabhorn]. re: typography (proper usuage of appostrophe and forms of words)., TLS and ALS 2pp.
  - 9. 1950, Sept. 4.Calistoga, Ca. Porter to Carl Rollins re: typography., TL 3pp.
  - 10. 1950-51, Dec., Jan.NP. [Porter] to __________(?)., TL 1p.
  - 11. ND., Saturday. NP. Porter to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
- GOUDY, FREDERIC (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - : 1. ND., March 27.Marlboro, [N.Y.]. Goudy to Colt Press., ALS 1p.
  - 2. ND., April 29.Marlboro, [N.Y.]. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 3pp.
  - 3. ND., May 9.Marlboro, [N.Y.]. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 2pp.
  - 4. ND., June 10.Marlboro, N.Y. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 5. ND., Oct. 24.Marlboro, [N.Y.]. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn]. re: typography., ALS 2pp.
  - 6. ND., Nov. 29.Marlboro, N.Y. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 2pp.
  - 7. 1941, Jan. 15.Marlboro, [N.Y.]. Goudy to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 4pp.
  - 8. Page of drawings of possible monograms for Jane Grabhorn.
- JEFFERS, ROBINSON (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1. 1935, June 21.Taos, New Mexico. Robinson Jeffers to Jane Grabhorn., ALS 1p.
- KEES, WELDON (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1. 1942, June 23.Saratoga Springs, N.Y. Weldon Kees to Bill Roth re: typography., TLS 2pp.
- KNOPF, MRS. ALFRED A. (BLANCHE) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1. 1952, Oct. 1.New York. Mrs. Alfred A. Knopf to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
- MILLER, HENRY (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1. [Harton], Virginia [Rogers] to [Henry Miller] re: Colussus... 1941, Nov. 6.Chicago, Ill., 1p. ALS.
  - 2. 1941, Nov. 22.Brooklyn, N.Y. Helen Pope to Politis re: Colossus..., TL 1p.
  - 3. 1941, Nov. 25.Washington, [D.C.]. Corinne(?) P_____(?) to Miller re: Colussus..., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1941, Nov. 28.New York, N.Y. Carlo Van Vechten to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus..., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1941, Nov. 29.New York, N.Y. M.J. Politis to [William] Roth re: Colussus..., TLS 4pp.
  - 6. 1941, Dec. 2.Hollywood, Ca. Hilaire _____(?) to Henry [Miller]. re: Colussus.., ALS 1p.
  - 7. 1941, Dec. 8.New York, N.Y. D_____(?) to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus.... ALS.
  - 8. 1941, Dec. 9.New York, N.Y. Rosalind Constable to [Henry] Miller re: the book Colussus..., TLS 1p.
  - 9. 1941, Dec. 16.Altadena, Ca. Robert Swasey to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus..., TLS 3pp.
  - 10. 1941, Dec. 31.New London, Conn. John Rogers Shuman (United States Coast Guard Academy) to Henry Miller re: Colussus. and Shuman's book White Landscape., TLS 1p.
  - 11. 1942, Jan. 9.Hanover, New Hampshire. Herbert F. West to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus..., ALS 2pp.
  - 12. 1944, Jan. 9.NP. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 13. 1945, July 11.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn] re: prospective books., TLS 1p.
  - 14. 1945, Aug. 17.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn] re: Maurizius book., TLS 1p.
  - 15. 1945, Aug. 18.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 16. 1945, Aug. 23.Book dedication to Keith and Virginia Evans. (typed).
  - 17. 1945, Nov. 11.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., PCS 1p.
  - 18. 1946, Feb. 29.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn] re: Maurizius book., TLS 1p.
  - 19. 1948, May 5.[Big Sur, Ca.]. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 20. ND., Nov. 25.NP. Joe Sadon to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus... ALS.
  - 21. ND.New Iberia, Louisiana. Hall Weeks to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus..., TLS. 3pp
  - 22. ND.[New Iberia, Louisiana]. [Hall Weeks] to Smitty re: Colussus..., TL 1p.
  - 23. ND [1941],Saturday. Chicago, ILL. [Eleanor Howard] to Henry [Miller] re: Colussus... AL.
  - 24. ND.NP. Bessie [Brener] to Henry [Miller] re: the book The Colussus of Maroussi., ALS 2pp.
  - 25. ND., Monday.Big Sur, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 26. ND., Thursday.[Big Sur, Ca.]. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 27. ND., July 9.Hollywood, Ca. Henry Miller to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., ALS 2pp.
  - 28. Typescript of part of Air Conditioned Nightmare.
  - 29. Typescript - Autobiographical Note by Henry Miller.
  - 30. 1945, Oct.Agreement between Henry Miller and Colt Press concerning the book Maurizius Forever.
  - 31. Printed autobiography by Henry Miller - An Autobiographical Note.
  - 32. 21 photos, sketches and watercolors by Miller.
- RANSOM, WILL (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1. 1937, Sept. 18.Buffalo, N.Y. Will Ransom to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1937, Oct. 31.Buffalo, N.Y. Will Ransom to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1938, Jan. 29.Buffalo, N.Y. Will Ransom to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1938, Feb. 23.Buffalo, N.Y. Will Ransom to Jane Grabhorn. TLS.
- ROLLINS, CARL PURINGTON (YALE UNIVERSITY PRESS) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1. 1937, Sept. 10.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1938, June 10.NP. Rollins to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1938, Nov. 30.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 2p.
  - 4. 1940, Oct. 6.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 3p.
  - 5. 1941, Mar. 1.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 6. 1941, Apr. 2.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 7. 1942, Feb. 2.New Haven, Conn. Rollins to Jane [Grabhorn] re: the book McTEAGUE, typography., TLS 3p.
  - 8. ND.NP. Rollins to Jumbo ([Jane Grabhorn])., tel. 1p.
- ROTH WILLIAM (Box 1, Folder Folder 16b.)
  - 1. 1943, May 19.NP. Louise Stivers to Wm. Roth. TL.
  - 2. 1944, Aug. 21.NP. [S.F., Ca.]. Louise Stivers to Wm. Roth. TL.
  - 3. 1944, Aug. 21.NP. [S.F., Ca.]. Louise Stivers to Wm. Rothe re: Colt Press accounts receivable - encl. 10pp. TL.
  - 4. Agreement: 1943, Oct. 1,between Jane Grabhorn & Wm. Roth.
- SAROYAN, WILLIAM (Box 1, Folder Folder 17.)
  - 1. 1938, Jan 23.San Francisco, Ca. Saroyan to Jane [Grabhorn] re: typography., TLS. 1p.
  - 2. 1938, Jan 26.San Francisco, Ca. Saroyan to Jane [Grabhorn] re: poetry, possibility of publishing other literary pieces., TLS. 2p.
  - 3. 1939, Feb. 10.San Francisco, Ca. Saroyan to Jane Grabhorn re: typography., TLS. 1p.
  - 4. 1947, June 9.San Francisco, Ca. Saroyan to Jane and Bob [Grabhorn]. PCS
  - 5. 1947, June 19.San Francisco, Ca. Saroyan to Jane [Grabhorn]. PCS.
  - 6. 1963, Nov. 18.Paris, France. Saroyan to [Jane] Grabhorn re: various literary projects., TLS 1p.
  - 7. Draft of title page and contents page for a compilation of short plays by Saroyan.
- SCHAD, ROBERT O. (ROUNCE & COFFIN CLUB) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1. 1940, March 7.Los Angeles, Ca.(?). Schad to Colt Press re: use of Colt Press books in Western Books exhibit., TLS 1p.
- STEINBECK, JOHN (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1. ND.Los Gatos, Ca. Steinbeck to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 2. ND. Los Gatos, Ca. Steinbeck to Jane Grabhorn. ALS.
- STEVENSON, GOVERNOR ADLAI (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1. 1954, Dec. 27.Chicago, Ill. Stevenson to Mr. & Mrs. Grabhorn., TLS. 1p.
  - 2. 1956, Dec. 8.Chicago, Ill. Stevenson to Grabhorn Press., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1958, Mar. 11.Chicago, Ill. Stevenson to Mr. & Mrs. Robert Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1958, April 10.Chicago, Ill. Stevenson to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1958, June 13.Chicago, Ill. Stevenson to Mr. & Mrs. Robert Grabhorn. TLS with typed cover note: Carol Evans, Secretary to Gov. Stevenson, to Mr. & Mrs. Grabhorn., 2pp.
- TINKER, EDWARD LAROCQUE (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1. 1940, June 28.New York, N.Y. Tinker to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 2pp.
  - 2. ND.,Friday. New York. Tinker to [Jane Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 3. ND.,Saturday. [New York]. Tinker to [Jane Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
- WAGNER, HENRY (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1. 1941, March 17.San Marino, Ca. H.R. Wagner to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. ND., Jan. 10. San Marino, Ca. Wagner to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
- WALKER, FRANKLIN (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1. 1939, Oct. 14.San Diego, Ca. Walker to Jane Grabhorn re: prospects of a book about Bierce., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1940, Mar. 30.San Diego, Ca. Walker to Jane Grabhorn re: book about Bierce., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1940, Sept. 27.Eugene, Oregon. Walker to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1941, April 3.Eugene, Oregon. Walker to Jane Grabhorn re: publication of book about Bierce., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1941, April 12.Eugene, Oregon. Walker to Jane [Grabhorn] re: Bierce book., TLS 1p
- WARDE, BEATRICE (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1. 1962, July 8.S.F., Ca. Warde to Jane Grabhorn., ANS 1p.
  - 2. 1965, June 28.Chicago, Ill. Warde to Jane [Grabhorn]., ANS 2pp.
- WILSON, EDMUND (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1. 1943, May 24.Wellfleet, Mass. Wilson to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1946, July 29.Wellfleet, Mass. Wilson to [Jane] Grabhorn., ALS 1p.
  - 3. 1946, Dec. 1.Minden, Nevada. Wilson to [Jane] Grabhorn., ALS 1p.
  - 4. 1948, April 21.Wellfleet, Mass. Wilson to [Jane] Grabhorn re: publishing of Wilson's book., ALS 1p.
  - 5. 1949, July 8.Wellfleet, Mass. Wilson to [Jane] Grabhorn re: publishing of Wilson's material., ALS 1p.
- WINTERS, JANET LEWIS (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1. 1943, Feb. 24.Los Altos, Ca. Winters to Jane Grabhorn re: writing., ALS 3pp.
  - 2. 1946, July 23.Los Altos, Ca. Winters to Jane [Grabhorn] re: finances., ALS 2pp.
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE: (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1. AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF GRAPHICS ARTS: 1. 1937, Nov. 4.New York, N.Y. Ruth S. Grammiss(?) to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1942, Nov. 18.New York, N.Y. Executive Secretary (name illegible) to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 2. CARPENTER PAPER CO: 1. 1942, Feb. 18.S.F., Ca. W.R. Osburn Jr. (Credit Manager) to Colt Press., TLS 1p.
  - 3. CASTRO, DANIEL F: 1. 1945, Sept. 25.Berkeley, Ca. Castro to [Jane] Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 4. COLT PRESS
    - 1. 1943, June 23.S.F., Ca. Louise Stivers (Bookkeeper) to Collector of Internal Revenue re: taxes., TL 1p.
    - 2. 1944, Jan.12.S.F., Ca. Louise Stivers (accountant & bookkeeper) to Sales Tax Division., TL 1p.
    - 3. 1944, Jan. 12.Same as # 2.
    - 4. 1944, April 4.S.F., Ca. Louise [Stivers] to Jane & Bob [Grabhorn] re: taxes., TLS 1p.
    - 5. 1945, June 25.[S.F., Ca.]. Colt Press to Louis Jeffreys., TL 1p.
    - 6. 1944, Oct. 31.[S.F.], Ca. [Louise Stivers] to Consumers' Book Cooperative., TL 1p.
    - 7. 1946, Jan. 7.S.F., Ca. Louise [Stivers] to Jane & Bob [Grabhorn] re: taxes., TLS 1p.
    - 8. 1946, June 19.[S.F., Ca.]. Louise Stivers to McMurray's. TLs
    - 9. ND.,S.F., Ca. Colt Press to State of California, Board of Equalization, Sales & Use Tax Return., TL 1p.
  - 5. DRAKE, DOROTHY M: 1. 1940, Mar. 28.Drake (Librarian, Scripps College) to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 6. DEVANS, HERBERT: 1. 1939, Dec. 1.Berkeley, Ca. Evans to Jane Grabhorn re: dating of Jumbo Press books. (includes list of Grabhorn books printed under Jumbo Press name., TLS 3pp.
  - 7. FEDERAL SECURITY AGENCY, SOCIAL SECURITY BOARD: 1. 1942, July 9.S.F., Ca. C.E.C. Burnett, manager, to Colt Press., TLS 1p.
  - 8. GRABHORN, JANE
    - 1. 1944, June 8.NP. Jane [Grabhorn] to Louise [Stivers]., TN 1p.
    - 2. 1944, Sept. 6.S.F. Ca. J.G. to Judge [UNK], TLS 1p.
    - 3. 1946, Nov. 16.S.F. Ca. J.G. to Roy., TLS 2pp.
  - 9. GROLIER, CLUB:1. 1937, Oct. 23.New York. Ruth S. Grammiss(?) to Jane Grabhorn. TLS.
  - 10. H. WOLFF BOOK MFG CO., INC: 1. 1941, Dec. 2.New York, N.Y. Ernst Reichl to Jane Grabhorn re: printing costs for the book The Pragmatic Test., TLS 2pp.
  - 11. HEGNEMAN(?), ANNE: 1. ND.New York, N.Y. Hegneman to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 12. von HAGEN, V. WOLFGANG: 1. 1939,Berkeley, Ca. von hagen to Jane Grabhorn re: printing of Melville book., TLS 1p.
  - 13. HARCOURT, BRACE & CO., INC: 1. 1940, Oct. 29.New York Harcourt Brace & Co. to Colt Press re: The American Songbag., TLS 1p.
  - 14. HOGAN, BILL (SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE): 1. 1971, Mar. 25.[S.F., Ca.]. Hogan to Jane [Grabhorn] re: Bill Saroyan - xerox of autograph note from Saroyan to Hogan enclosed., TNS 1p.
  - 15. JONAS, CHARLES: 1. 1939, July 15.Evanston, Ill. Jonas to Jane Grabhorn re: dime novels., TLS 2pp.
  - 16. JOSSELYN, MARJORIE: 1. ND., April 11.Redwood City, Ca. Josselyn to [Jane] Grabhorn., ALS 2pp.
  - 17. KITTREDGE, WILLIAM A: 1. 1941, May 20.Evanston, Ill. Kittredge to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 18. LOVEJOY
    - 1. 1939, June 8.Pacific Grove, Ca. Lovejoy to Jane Grabhorn. re: book Short Road., PCS 1p.
    - 2. ND., June 16.Pacific Grove, Ca. Lovejoy to [Jane] Grabhorn re: the book Short Road., TNS 1p.
  - 19. MACKENZIE & HARRIS, INC.: 1. 1937, Oct. 8.S.F., Ca. Carroll T. Harris to J[ane] Grabhorn re: Jumbo Press., TLS 1p.
  - 20. McMURRAY'S BOOKSHOP: 1. 1946, May 23.Dallas, Texas. Elizabeth Ann McMurray to Colt Press., TNS 1p.
  - 21. THE MISSOURI STORE COMPANY: 1. ND.Columbia, Missouri. R.E. Lucas, President, to [Colt Press]., TLS 1p.
  - 22. ROBINSON, NOWELL & CO.
    - 1. 1942, Jan. 22.S.F., Ca. Robinson, Nowell & Co. to Colt Press re: tax returns., TLS 1p.
    - 2. 1943, Nov. 9.S.F., Ca. Robinson, Nowell & Co. to Colt Press., TNS 1p.
  - 23. QUERCUS PRESS: 1. 1938, July 20.San Mateo, Ca. Ted and Frances Lilenthal to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 24. SPARKS, ROBERT W. (UNIVERSITY OF HAWAII PRESS): 1. 1970 Jan. 14.Honolulu, Hawaii. Sparks to [Jane] Grabhorn., TNS 1p.
  - 25. TOWNSEND, DOREEN: 1. 1937, July 12.Berkeley, Ca. Townsend to Jane Grabhorn., ANS 1p.
  - 26. WHALE, JAMES: 1. 1955, April 21.Pacific Palisades, Ca. Whale to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 4pp.
  - 27. UNKNOWN
    - 1. 1945, Mar. 6.NP. [Louise Stivers(?)] to Jane & Bob [Grabhorn] re: taxes., TL 1p.
    - 2. 1945, Jan. 9.NP. [Louise Stivers(?)] to Bob & Jane [Grabhorn] re: income taxes., TL 1p.
- MISC. CORRESPONDENCE - ARRANGED CHRONOLOGICALLY (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1. 1920, May 27.NP. Jane (?) to Mother., ALS 2pp.
  - 2. 1934, May 9.Hollywood, Ca. Bill to Jane & Bob [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1937, July 2.Berkeley, Ca. W_____(?) B_____(?) to Grabhorns, Jumbo Press., PCS 2pp.
  - 4. 1937, Sept. 20.New York, N.Y. _____(?), Chairman of the American Institute of Graphic Arts to Mrs. Martha Jane Grabhorn re: membership for Mrs. Grabhorn in Institute., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1937, Nov. 22.New York, N.Y. Philip C. Duschnes, Rare Books & First Editions, to Mr. H.R. Wagner re: special edition of Bookmaking on the Distaff Side., TLS 1p.
  - 6. 1938, Jan. 12.New York, N.Y. Jack Reynolds to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 7. 1938, Feb. 1.Berkeley, Ca. Wilder Bentley to Bob and Jane [Grabhorn] re: printing., TL 2pp.
  - 8. 1939, July 21.Berkeley, Ca. Wilder Bentley to Jane [Grabhorn] re: possibilities for publishing mansucript by Wolfgang von Hagen., TLS 2pp.
  - 9. 1941, Nov. 18.New York, N.Y. Nancy Booth Craig, National Broadcasting Co., Inc. to Colt Press re: transcript of material describing book The Epicure in Mexico. encl., TLS 3pp.
  - 9a. 1943, Nov 4SF Ca Brobeck Phleger & Harrison (Howard J. Finn) to Al McCarthy re: agreement between colt Press and Wm. Roth. TL
  - 10. 1943, Dec. 20.New York, N.Y. Karl Kup, Chairman American Institute of Graphic Arts to Jane Grabhonn re: selection of the book The Last Man for an exhibit., TLS 1p.
  - 11. 1943, Dec. 29.San Francisco, Ca. Jane Grabhorn to Carl [Karl] Kup re: selection of the Last Man for an exhibit., TLS 1p.
  - 12. 1951, Dec. 22.London, England. Teddy [Victor Reinganum] to Jane Grabhorn re: J.G.'s plan for trip overseas., TLS 2pp.
  - 13. 1952, Feb. 20.Hammersmith, England. _____(?) _____(?) to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 4pp.
  - 14. 1953, Oct. 31.New York, N.Y. Bennett [Cerf?] to Jane Grabhorn. tel., 1p.
  - 15. 1954, Dec. 30.San Francisco, Ca. Red Beans and Louis Satchmo Armstrong to Jane Grabhorn. tel., 1p.
  - 16. 1956, Feb. 7.Palo Alto, Ca. Jeannette M. Hitchcock, Chief-Division of Special Collections to Jackson Burke re: Colt Press show., TL 1p.
  - 17. 1957, Aug. 30.NP. Bob _____(?) to Jane [Grabhorn] re: book about cats., TLS 2pp.
  - 18. 1963, Nov. 16.NP. Unknown [Don] to Jane [Grabhorn] re: Truman & Kennedy., TL 3pp.
  - 19. 1963, Nov. 29.NP. Don to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 20. 1964, March 21.Neuilly-S/Seine, France. Alain Geruey to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 21. 1964, Nov. 16.Washington, D.C. Bill [Roth] to Mrs. Robert [Jane] Grabhorn., ALS 4pp.
  - 22. 1964, Dec. 7.San Francisco, Ca. Jane Grabhorn to Mr. Roth re: Grabhorn play Gracious Living., TL 2pp.
  - 23. [1964].San Francisco, Ca. Jane Grabhorn to William Roth re: production and publication of Grabhorn's play The Brothers, The Mothers., TL 3pp.
  - 24. 1968, June 12.San Francisco, Ca. Jack Cummings to Robert Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 25. 1968, July 11.NP. Deano (?) to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 26. 1968, July 22.San Francisco, Ca. Ruth Teiser to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 27. 1969, Jan. 22.Pleasantville, New York. Blake Clark, Editor - Reader's Digest to Jane [Grabhorn].
  - 28. 1969, May 7.Palo Alto, Ca. J_____(?) H_____(?) to [Jane Grabhorn]., ALS 4pp.
  - 29. 1970, Aug. 14.Oakland, Ca. Lois Rather to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 30. 1972, Feb. 7.San Francisco, Ca. Andrew Hoyem to Paul C. Steele re: typography. TLS xerox copy with note Written by Jane Grabhorn., 2pp.
  - 31. 1972, Feb. 14.Barnabus, West Virginia. [Paul C. Steele] to Andrew Hoyem re: publishing and printing costs., TL (xerox copy) frag. 1p.
  - 32. 1972, Feb. 15.Barnabus, West Virginia. Paul C. Steele to Andrew Hoyem., TLS 1p.
  - 33. 1972, Sept. 24.Huntington Beach, Ca. Mildred Yorba MacArthur (Mrs. Horacio Serrano) to Jane., ALS 4pp.
  - 34. 1973, Feb. 12.Bronxville, N.Y. Valenti Angelo to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 35. 1973, Mar. 28.Columbia, S.C. Bob (Robert E. Bell) to Jane & Bob Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 36. 1973, May 2.Berkeley, Ca. Steve Corey to Mr. & Mrs. Grabhorn., ALS 2pp.
  - 37. ND., Aug. 29.Los Angeles, Ca. Fred W. Dwart to Jane Grabhorn., ALS 2pp.
  - 38. ND., April 9.NP. Carolyn Coggins to Jane [Grabhorn], ALS 2pp.
  - 39. ND.NP. Melina Mercouri to [Jane Grabhorn(?)]., AN 1p.
    Allen
  - 40. ND.,Thursday. Kentfield, Ca. Dorothy & Lew(?) to Jane Grabhorn., ALS 1p.
    Allen Press
  - 41. ND.NP. Joan(?) to Bob [Grabhorn]., ANS 1p.
  - 42. ND., Nov. 18.New York. Marion R_____(?) to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 43. ND., Jan. 16.Mill Valley, Ca. Phyllis to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 44. ND.Huntington, [Genland]. [Earl of] Sandwich (George Montagu) to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 45. ND.San Francisco, Ca. William M. Roth to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 2pp.
  - 46. ND.Washington, D.C. William Roth to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 3pp.
  - 47. ND.NP. Andrew Hoyem to Mr. Steele., TLS 1p.
  - 48. ND.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 49. ND., May 24.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane Grabhorn., TLS 1p.
  - 50. ND., Aug. 15.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 51. ND.,Thursday. San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 52. ND., Nov. 9.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 53. ND., April 17.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Prez [Jane Grabhorn(?)]., TLS 1p.
  - 54. ND., Dec. 12.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Grabhor, TLS 1p.
  - 55. ND.,Monday. San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 56. ND., April 4.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Prez [J.G.]., TLS 1p.
  - 57. ND., March 28.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 58. ND., Dec. 20.San Francisco, Ca. Herb Caen to Jane [Grabhorn]., TLS 1p.
  - 59. ND.,NP. Jane [Grabhorn] to David., TLS 2pp.
  - 60. ND.,Monday. [S.F., Ca.]. Jane Grabhorn to Betty., ANS 1p.
  - 61. ND.NP. Valenti Angelo to Bob & Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 1p.
  - 62. ND.,Sunday. NP. Jane [Grabhorn] to Babies., ALS 4pp.
  - 63. ND.,Sunday. NP. Jane (?) [Grabhorn] to Friends re: trip abroad., ALS 10pp.
  - 64. ND., Jan. 14.Van Couver. Jane [Grabhorn] to Shop(?)., ALS 2pp.
  - 65. ND.NP. [Jane Grabhorn] to Unknown re: trip abroad., ALS 7pp.
  - 66. ND.Hinchingbrooke, Huntingdon. [Earl of Sandwich?] to Jane [Grabhorn]., ALS 4pp.
  - 67. ND.Hinchingbrooke, Huntingdon. Same as # 66.
  - 68. ND.NP. Ken P_____(?) to?. TLS
  - 69. ND.NP. Unknown to unknown, AL letter fragment
- FINANCIAL PAPERS